# ROHINI PATARE

Pune 411057, Maharashtra India ♦ (+91)-9503290330 ♦ rohinipatare03@gmail.com github.com/rohinipatare | linkedin.com/in/rohinipatare | myportfolio

#### **Profile**

Dedicated, passionate Blockchain developer with 2 years of experience in web development looking to develop comprehensive blockchains to support organizations. Re-entering the workforce after taking some time off to provide care to a disabled family member while staying engaged with the teaching for a reputed school in the locality & through occasional freelance work.

## **Development Skills**

Solidity, Ethereum, Hyperledger Fabric, Cryptography, Truffle, Hardhat, Defi, IPFS, web3.js, ReactJS, NodeJS, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

## **Project Work**

- Decentralized Application for Elections using Blockchain (2024): The Decentralized Voting System using Ethereum Blockchain is a secure, transparent & cost-effective solution for conducting elections for tamper-proof voting records, enabling users to cast their votes remotely while maintaining anonymity and preventing fraud.
- File Storage & Sharing DApp (2024):Developed a project that expedites decentralized File upload and sharing on the blockchain using Solidity for the smart contract and React for the front-end interface. It enables users to securely upload files to IPFS (InterPlanetary File System) and share access with specific users through smart contract functionality.

# Certifications

- Professional Certificate Program in Blockchain Development by IIT Kanpur View Cert
- Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHCE) View Cert
- Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA) View Cert
- UI Design, Growth School View Cert

## Work Experience

# Makebot Robotics, Mumbai

2018 - 2020

#### - Associate Software Analyst

- Conducted comprehensive market research and analysis, presenting key findings using LAMP Stack to B2C e-commerce Marketplace for STEM products & services & developed user appealing website for organizational requirement into effective application design and System Development.
- Provided adequate troubleshooting & created proper documentation for reference purpose of each project with results
   & problems faced during requirement gathering till deployment on AWS.. This shortened learning time by 19 days
- Developed a scratch based application for block based robotic programming,

# **Teaching for A School**

- Computer Teacher 2021 - 2024

- Provided 24/7 in-home care for a family member during treatment for a medical condition until a full recovery along
  with staying engaged with the teaching for a reputed school in the locality & through occasional freelance work.
- Completed Professional Blockchain Development Program from IIT Kanpur, Enhanced my Development skills by creating projects, completed certifications.

#### Education

### **Bachelor of Engineering (B.E)**

2014 - 2018

Computer Science and Engineering from Dr. BAMU University

74.06%

#### Awards & Achievements

- Tech Unicorn Award from Makebot robotics
- JUDGE for National Robotic Competition MakeX
- 2nd price in Smart India Hackathon, by Government of India